Artur Rodzinski Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Annotated Music, circa 1868-1956, bulk 1932-1947 (Box 13-43; 52-59)
  - Walton, William
    - [Concerto, violin, B minor]
      - Concerto for violin and orchestra. London: Oxford University Press, 1945, 172 p.; Authoritative version. (Box-folder 43/1)
  - Ward, Robert
    - [Symphony, no. 1]
      - First symphony. New York: American Music Center Inc., 1942, 72 p.; Juilliard Edition. (Box-folder 43/2)
  - Weinberg, Jacob
    - The Gettysburg address: a symphonic ode for baritone solo, chorus and orchestra: op. 36. New York: M. Witmark & Sons, 1936, 32 p. (Box-folder 58/2)
  - Weinberger, Jaromír
    - [Svanda dudák. polka]
      - Polka and fugue from the opera “Shvanda.” New York: Associated Music Publishers, 1942, 62 p.; Transposed edition by the composer. (Box-folder 43/3)
    - Under the spreading chestnut tree: variations and fugue on an old English tune for full orchestra. New York: Boosey & Hawkes Inc., 1939, 56 p. (Box-folder 43/4)
  - Wilder, Alec
    - Piece for orchestra (in three movements) [S.l.: s.n., n.d.], 60 p. (Box-folder 58/3)
  - Zádor, Eugene
    - [Rondo, orchestra]
      - Rondo für Orchester. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1934, 54 p. (Box-folder 43/5)
    - Sinfonia technica: partitura. Wien: Universal-Edition A.G., 1932, 114 p. (Box-folder 43/6)
- Scrapbooks, 1919-1944, bulk 1919-1933, 1944 (Box 48-51)
  The four scrapbooks include newspaper clippings, magazine articles and programs. The majority of the information concerns performance announcements, performance reviews, interviews and biographical information. Scrapbook 1 (1919-25) is comprised of articles in Polish with the majority relating to performances at the Teatr Wielki w Warszawie [Warsaw Opera] and the Lwów Opera. Scrapbook 2 (1925-30) consists of documents in English, German, and Italian that record Rodzinski’s time with the Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra, the Philadelphia Orchestra, the Curtis Institute of Music, the Pennsylvania Grand Opera Company, the Stanley Music Club, the Rochester Philharmonic, and guest appearances in New York, Detroit, Los Angeles, San Francisco, and Santa Monica County, California. Scrapbook 3 (1930-33) contains materials in English and an item in Hebrew that document the Los Angeles Symphony Orchestra, the Hollywood Bowl, the Young People’s Concert Series, the Cleveland Orchestra, the San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, and the Philadelphia Orchestra. Scrapbook 4 (1944) covers Rodzinski’s visit to the United States Rubber Plant in Woonsocket, Rhode Island, with the newspaper clippings in English.
  The series is arranged in chronological order.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1919-1925 (Box 48)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1925-1930 (Box 49)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1930-1933 (Box 50)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1944 (Box 51)
- Subject Files, 1919-1989, bulk 1929-1958 (Box 11-12; 44-47; 60-62)
  This series contains newspaper clippings, magazine articles, programs, photographs, tickets, schedules, brochures, advertisements, a poster, business cards, catalogs, lists of composers’ works, a drawing and announcements. In addition, there are descriptions of Shostakovich’s opera Lady Macbeth of the Mzensk District and the process Rodzinski took to perform it. Most of the articles are announcements or reviews of Rodzinski’s performances in the United States, Europe, and Latin America. Other themes include biographical information, comparisons to other conductors, reviews of composers’ works, interviews, and Rodzinski’s travels. The majority of the documents are written in English or Polish, but also include Italian, German, Russian, and French.
  The series is arranged alphabetically.
  - 35-letni Jubileusz Towarzystwa Śpiewu Lutnia, at the Masonic Temple in Detroit, Michigan, program, 1943 (Box-folder 11/12)
  - Adirondacks Festival of the Arts, 1947 (Box-folder 60/8)
  - Antena 3, no. 33 (September 16, 1936) (Box-folder 44/1)
  - L’Approdo musicale 1, no. 4 (October-December 1958) (Box-folder 11/13)
  - The Barber of Seville, 1935 (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Barroud, Henry, n.d. (Box-folder 11/15)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1989 (Box-folder 11/16)
  - Bliss, Arthur, Sir, n.d., Note on his Concert suite from Checkmate. (Box-folder 11/17)
  - Breitkopf & Härtel advertisement, n.d. (Box-folder 11/18)
  - Budapest concert, 1937 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1937 (Box-folder 11/20)
  - Chicago, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 44/2, 61/4)
  - Chicago Symphony Orchestra, 1947-1950, 1989, Includes programs and a statement of the Friends of Chicago Symphony. (Box-folder 11/21, 44/3, 60/9, 61/5)
  - Cleveland Orchestra programs, 1933-1943 (Box-folder 44/4, 60/10, 61/6)
  - Columbia Records Inc., 1945-1947, Includes publicity materials such as brochures, catalogs, advertisements and a poster. (Box-folder 11/22, 60/11)
  - Concert Management Willard Matthews, 1935-1943, Includes brochures featuring Gertrude Gibson, Phyllis Kraeuter, Aurora Mauro-Cottone, Thomas Richner and Avron Twerdowsky. (Box-folder 11/23)
  - Cowell, Henry, n.d., Notes on his American Pipers. (Box-folder 11/24)
  - Edwin F. Kalmus, 1927-1928, 1938, Catalog of all miniature scores, price lists of scores. (Box-folder 11/25)
  - Elektra in New York, 1937 (Box-folder 11/26)
  - Ernani and Eros I Psyche, 1919 (Box-folder 44/5)
  - Eugen Onegin, 1928 (Box-folder 60/12)
  - Eugenio Onieghin at Teatro alla Scala in Milan, Italy, program, 1954 (Box-folder 61/7)
  - Faust at Teatro alla Scala in Milan, Italy, 1954 (Box-folder 61/8)
  - Festivale Salzvurskie [Salzburg Festival], 1936 (Box-folder 11/27, 60/13)
  - Festivalu Wiedeńskim in Vienna, n.d. (Box-folder 11/28)
  - Filharmonia Warszawska [National Orchestra of Warsaw], n.d. (Box-folder 44/6)
  - Florence, Italy, 1952 (Box-folder 60/14)
  - Goldschmidt, Berthold, brochure, 1931 (Box-folder 11/29)
  - Goossens, Eugene, Sir, n.d., A list of his works. (Box-folder 11/30)
  - Guerra e Pace [War and Peace] at Maggio musicale fiorentino in Florence, Italy, 1953 (Box-folder 44/7, 61/9)
  - Havana, 1949 (Box-folder 61/10)
  - Hindemith, Paul, n.d., Contains performance suggestions for his op. 44, no. 4. (Box-folder 11/31)
  - Illustracye, foreign language, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 44/8, 60/15)
  - Interviews, honors, and memorials, 1928-1958 (Box-folder 44/9, 60/16-17, 61/11)
  - Jarecki, Tadeusz, n.d. (Box-folder 11/32)
  - Katerina Ismailova, program, 1965 (Box-folder 44/10, 61/12)
  - Kondracki, Michal, n.d. (Box-folder 11/33)
  - Lady Macbeth of the Mzensk Distric, 1934-1935, Contains four photographs, a description of acquiring the score, a description of scenes and programs.; Photographs with Cleveland Orchestra: 1) Rodzinski with the cast, 2) Act 4, scene 9, 3) unknown scene, 4) the set. (Box-folder 11/34, 44/11-14, 61/13-14)
  - Lake Placid (N.Y.), 1958 (Box-folder 11/35)
  - Lidov, P. Tania,, 1942 (Box-folder 11/36)
  - Lilien, Ignace, 1949, Catalog of his works. (Box-folder 11/37)
  - Liszt, Franz, 1931, Comments on his work by Jenö Hubay. (Box-folder 11/38)
  - Lloyd, George, 1945 (Box-folder 11/39)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra, 1929 (Box-folder 11/40, 45/1, 60/18)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra, program, 1930 (Box-folder 11/41, 45/2, 60/19)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra, 1931 (Box-folder 45/3, 60/20)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 11/42, 45/4, 60/21)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra program, blank postcard and blank stationary, n.d. (Box-folder 11/43, 45/5)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra, 1929-1933 (Box-folder 62/1)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra, drawing, around 1933 (Box-folder 60/22)
  - Lyric Opera of Chicago, 1958 (Box-folder 45/6)
  - Lyric Theater of Chicago, 1955 (Box-folder 11/44)
  - Maggio musicale fiorentino, programs and schedules, 1957 (Box-folder 11/45)
  - Miami Health Institute, 1949, Business card of Dr. G.F. Ehrline. (Box-folder 11/46)
  - Milwaukee, 1947 (Box-folder 62/2)
  - Montreal, 1951 (Box-folder 11/47)
  - Montserrat (Spain), n.d., A brochure. (Box-folder 11/48)
  - Music Courier 98, no. 9 (February 28, 1929)(cover only) (Box-folder 60/23)
  - Music News interviews Rodzinski, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 45/7)
  - Naples, Italy, n.d., A brochure. (Box-folder 11/49)
  - La Nazione Italiana 115, no. 134 (July 6, 1953) (Box-folder 62/3)
  - New York Philharmonic programs, 1937-1946 (Box-folder 11/50)
  - New York Philharmonic program,1940 (Box-folder 60/24)
  - New York Philharmonic, 1942-1947 (Box-folder 62/4)
  - New York Philharmonic, 1944-1946, n.d. (Box-folder 45/8)
  - New York Philharmonic, 1947 (Box-folder 45/9-12)
  - “Opera stołeczna,” 1938 (Box-folder 45/13)
  - Orquesta Filarmónica de La Habana program, 1949 (Box-folder 11/51)
  - Orquesta Sinfónica Venezuela at Teatro Municipal (Caracas, Venezuela) program, 1951 (Box-folder 11/52)
  - Palomba, Lidia, 1952-1957, Announcements about and interviews conducted with Palomba. (Box-folder 11/53)
  - Panorama 2, no. 33 (July 3, 1932) (Box-folder 45/14)
  - Paris, France, 1937 (Box-folder 45/15)
  - Philadelphia Orchestra, 1926 (Box-folder 45/16)
  - Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra program, 1948 (Box-folder 11/54)
  - Polish criticism and festivals, 1925-1946 (Box-folder 45/17, 60/25)
  - Polish miscellaneous clippings, 1919-1924, 1932 (Box-folder 45/18)
  - “Polish position outlined,” 1946 (Box-folder 11/55)
  - Polish Review 3, no. 38 (October 18, 1943) (Box-folder 46/1)
  - Pops symphony concert and Christmas benefit for Fort Logan Convalescent Hospital, program, 1944 (Box-folder 46/2)
  - Prince Charles Hotel, n.d., Business card for George M. LeClere. (Box-folder 11/56)
  - Radiocorriere 25, no. 36 (September 1948) (Box-folder 46/3)
  - Radiocorriere 30, no. 1 (January 1953) (Box-folder 46/4)
  - Radiocorriere 31, no. 1 (January 1954) (Box-folder 46/5)
  - Radiocorriere 31, no. 7 (February 1954) (Box-folder 46/6)
  - Radiocorriere 32, no. 13 (March-April 1955) (Box-folder 46/7)
  - Radiocorriere 33, no.16 (April 1956) (Box-folder 46/8)
  - Radiocorriere 34, no. 14 (April 1957) (Box-folder 46/9)
  - Radiocorriere 35, no. 15 (April 1958) (Box-folder 46/10)
  - Radiocorriere 35, no. 26 (June-July 1958) (Box-folder 46/11)
  - Radiocorriere clippings, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 46/12)
  - Radiotelevisione Italiana, 1958 (Box-folder 46/13)
  - Ravinia Festival, 1936-1947, Includes program and seasons resume. (Box-folder 46/14, 60/26, 62/5)
  - Read, Gardner, 1938-1940, Brochures. (Box-folder 11/57)
  - Return to the United States, 1953, 1958 (Box-folder 46/15)
  - Rodzinski, Artur, 1937-1956 (Box-folder 46/16, 60/27)
  - Rodzinski scomparso [disappeared], 1958 (Box-folder 62/6)
  - Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, 1958 (Box-folder 11/58)
  - Rózsa, Miklós, 1936 (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Sala Konserwatorjum of Zofji Rudzkiej, program, 1922 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Salome with Rose Pauly in Chicago, 1940 (Box-folder 46/17, 62/7)
  - San Francisco Opera, 1949 (Box-folder 12/3)
  - San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, program, 1949 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Schelling, Ernest, 1923 (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Schubert, Franz, ca. 1937, Brochure on his Variationen in As-dur, op. 35. (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Shostakovich, Dmitriĩ Dmitrievich, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 46/18, 60/28)
  - Société des concerts du Conservatoire, brochure, 1949 (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Tannhäuser in Florence, Italy, 1953 (Box-folder 46/19)
  - Teatr Wielki w Warszawie [Warsaw Opera], 1922-1934 (Box-folder 46/20, 62/8)
  - Teatro alla Scala, 1958 (Box-folder 12/8)
  - Teatro comunale di Firenze, 1952-1956, 1989 (Box-folder 46/21, 62/9)
  - Teatro di San Carlo, programs, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 47/1-2, 62/10)
  - “A tenant scores welfare hotel,” n.d. (Box-folder 62/11)
  - “Theater: Alec Guinness as Dylan,” 1964 (Box-folder 62/12)
  - Time 49, no. 7 (February 17, 1947) (Box-folder 47/3)
  - “Tolstoi musicien,” n.d. (Box-folder 47/4)
  - Torino, Italy, Radio audizioni Italia, 1955-1957, Includes programs, tickets, brochure and schedule. (Box-folder 47/5-6, 62/13)
  - Tristan and Isolde in Chicago, program, 1947, 1958 (Box-folder 47/7, 62/14)
  - Tristano e Isotta [Tristan and Isolde] in Florence, Italy, programs, 1957 (Box-folder 47/8, 62/15)
  - Van Vactor, David, 1947, Brochures. (Box-folder 60/29)
  - Vatican concert, 1958 (Box-folder 47/9-10, 62/16)
  - Die Walkuere at the Metropolitan Opera, 1958 (Box-folder 47/11)
  - Wagner, Joseph Frederick, 1925-1938, Brochure and list of compositions. (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Wagons-lists//cook world travel service brochure, n.d. (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Wiadomości, 13, no. 48, 661 (November 30, 1958) (Box-folder 62/17)
  - Wiadomosci Literackie 11, no. 19, 546 (May 13, 1934) (Box-folder 62/18)
  - Wieniaswski, Henri, 1988 (Box-folder 47/12)
  - Williamsburg, Virginia, n.d., Photo-guide brochure. (Box-folder 12/11)
- Legal Documents, 1948-1951 (Box 12)
  The documents in this small series include visas, immigration forms, customs papers, property leases, documentation of residence, an agreement, and a list of exhibits for a court case. Some of the visas and customs papers are for Artur, Halina, and his son, Richard Rodzinski. Photographs of Halina and Richard are included in the Argentina immigration and customs records. The materials are in English, German and Spanish. Other legal documents, such as contracts, are found within the correspondence series.
  - American Embassy Polish visa application for Hanusz family, 1951 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Argentina immigration and customs records for Artur Rodzinski and family, 1950-1951, Includes photographs of Halina and Richard Rodzinski. (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Hessischer Rundfunk, 1951, An agreement. (Box-folder 12/14)
  - Income tax notes, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 12/15)
  - Lease on apartment in Manhattan, New York, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 12/16)
  - Lease on cottage in North Elba, New York, 1948 (Box-folder 12/17)
  - Lease on house in Havana, Cuba, 1949 (Box-folder 12/18)
  - List of exhibits for court, 1951 (Box-folder 12/19)
  - United Kingdom income tax form, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 12/20)
  - United Kingdom visa permit, 1948 (Box-folder 12/21)
- Miscellaneous, 1888-1956, bulk 1938-1949 (Box 12; 47)
  Included in this series are an address book, receipts, membership cards, lists, schedules of performances, notes, business cards, a painting and a price list. The materials are mainly in English, but also contain items in Italian, Polish and German.
  - Address book, n.d. (Box-folder 12/22)
  - American Moto-Scoot Co., Inc. parts price list, 1938 (Box-folder 12/23)
  - Cardinals with the Holy Roman Church list of names, n.d. (Box-folder 12/24)
  - Chicago Federation of Musicians membership card, 1949 (Box-folder 12/25)
  - Lake Placid Speed Skating Club membership card, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 12/26)
  - Newspapers and magazine list, n.d. (Box-folder 12/27)
  - Notebook, 1888-1944 (Box-folder 12/28)
  - Paduano, Giuseppe business card, n.d. (Box-folder 12/29)
  - Painting of unidentified person [both sides of leaf], n.d. (Box-folder 12/30)
  - Receipts for scores and recordings, 1930-1947 (Box-folder 12/31)
  - Receipts, miscellaneous, 1933, 1949 (Box-folder 12/32)
  - Schedules of performances, 1955-1956, n.d. (Box-folder 12/33)
  - Symphony orchestras, conductors and managers in the United States, Canada and Europe list, 1948 (Box-folder 47/13)